<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Khanh&#39;s Site</title>
    <description>Personal website of Dang Nam Khanh.</description>
    <link>http://www.dangnamkhanh.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.dangnamkhanh.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>editor for HDL</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you very much for reading this article and see you later.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2015 02:45:19 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.dangnamkhanh.com/blog/vim/emacs/2015/01/25/editor-for-HDL/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.dangnamkhanh.com/blog/vim/emacs/2015/01/25/editor-for-HDL/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first post on my own website. I just bought a domain yesterday then tried to figure out how to set up my website.
Firstly, I think I can setup with wordpress for fee but they required me to pay about 10$ per year for this service. So this is just too much because I already paid for my domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Formerly I maintained my personal website in github since last year. Therefore I think that I can use CNAME to point to this for free (it is amazing). I googled it and it is worked. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I put my old website which is actually a one-page html on my new domain but I think it&amp;rsquo;s just &amp;ldquo;unprofessionally&amp;rdquo;. Especially, I need to post some articles but using html and handle link is inconvenient. I tried to google again then find out that I can setup &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;jekyll&lt;/a&gt; to generate my website base on Markdown. I have a lot chances to do with Markdown in the past so it is just easy for me and closes to HTML. After wasting a morning, I finally finished it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I have new host for free with basical function (I think PHP doesn&amp;rsquo;t work here!). Since I am not professional blogger so I satisfy with this. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you very much for reading this article and see you later.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 02:41:19 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.dangnamkhanh.com/blog/2015/01/23/hello/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.dangnamkhanh.com/blog/2015/01/23/hello/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
