<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Khanh N. Dang</title>
    <description>Khanh&#39;s Site</description>
    <link>http://www.dangnamkhanh.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.dangnamkhanh.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 09:41:09 +0900</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 09:41:09 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Editing vector figure from MS Powerpoint to Latex with free software</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I used to draw in MS Visio for 4-5 years. This tool is quite strong for drawing and it support to export
into vector format (EPS or PDF) that you can include inside Latex easily with better quality. Obviously, 
you can find out some tools that support drawing then export Latex file. However if you still have to work 
with MS Word, Visio is best choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I moved to Japan then setup new machine without Visio (it probably cost me 30,000 JPY if I buy) so I have to
try drawing in Powerpoint. To be honest, drawing tool is powerpoint is really bad, you cannot add connection 
point, free-shape and so on. Furthermore, it import method is horrible. I normally import to MS Word with acceptable
quality but to Latex is not good at all. Figure pixel is easily to be broken and hard to deal with several scaling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried with some tool then find out &lt;a href=&quot;https://inkscape.org/ja/&quot;&gt;Inkscape&lt;/a&gt; and  how to deal with it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Export Powerpoint page to PDF figure: Save As -&amp;gt; Select PDF -&amp;gt; Select Option : Current Page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crop it by Inkscape (free software). Open PDF file -&amp;gt; Select region 
-&amp;gt; Crop by Ctrl + Shift + D -&amp;gt; Choose resize page to content -&amp;gt; Save as PDF.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore I can draw completely in Inkscape then export vector image now but 
I have to do with Powerpoint since my fellas still using it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P/S: For free software alternative of Visio, you can try &lt;a href=&quot;http://sourceforge.net/projects/dia-installer/&quot;&gt;Dia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I used to draw in MS Visio for 4-5 years. This tool is quite strong for drawing and it support to export
into vector format (EPS or PDF) that you can include inside Latex easily with better quality. Obviously, 
you can find out some tools that support drawing then export Latex file. However if you still have to work 
with MS Word, Visio is best choice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 08:59:59 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.dangnamkhanh.com/blog/import-vectorfigure-from-mspp-to-latex/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.dangnamkhanh.com/blog/import-vectorfigure-from-mspp-to-latex/</guid>
        
        <category>latex</category>
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>msoffice</category>
        
        <category>inkscape</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Bullet Journal</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of methods for tracking and managing our schedule. They are called as todo notes. 
We have tone of apps on mobile like Any.Do, Wunderlist, so on. We can use Evernote, text file to do it.
Some people (like me) use email as todo note. Another calendar apps, ex: google calendar is just awesome 
to schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year, I mostly used my email inbox and gcal to track my working progress as well as another events. To be honest,
this is the most effective system for me. Short, linking together, online, secure and so on. You can easily track on phone, 
laptop, desktop. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow this year I really that I am becoming to hate my devices because it costs a lot of my time. Every time I pick up my phone, 
I will check my email, calendar, facebook, website and ton of things. Further more, I cannot track back what I done last month, week 
and evaluate it. So, I changed to analogy stuff. Sound strange for computer engineering student but yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I use big notebook to do it. Write down everyday, month, year and so on. I feel so easy to to track my progress. I know how 
I work this week, what I have to enhance, what is the main problem. However, it is inconvenient if I bring my notebook to everywhere.
I really love it but I have to changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought a pocket calendar from school store and it works so well. It have monthly schedule, weekly schedule and daily. But (it always says but)
this pocket is to small to write. Sometime, I&amp;#39;ve done and scheduled ton of thing a day but will do nothing next day. And sometime I cannot understand what I wrote 
because it is to short to read. Damn it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried looking for another method on the internet and got &lt;a href=&quot;http://bulletjournal.com&quot;&gt;bullet journal&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GfRf43JTqY4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 

&lt;p&gt;I think this is just an awesome idea for noting. Everything is clear and easy to track. I will not be limited by line or something.
In another the word, this is just doing it in small notebook instead of big one. And the way to organize is just awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P/S: about the pen and notebooks, Japanese product is just simply the best (as my experience). I don&amp;#39;t know the name of notebook 
but I usually use Pilot and Uni-ball pen. I found a magic pen by Pilot which write similarly as water pen but erasable like pencil. Of course 
I don&amp;#39;t know the brand, just Pilot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edit (2015-03-11): I am now using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.midori-japan.co.jp/tr/&quot;&gt;Midori Traveller Notebook&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mpuni.co.jp/products/ballpoint_pens/gel/signo_cap/signo/um_151.html&quot;&gt;Uni-ball Signo DX&lt;/a&gt;. 
Midori notebook is easy to mix-up with a lot of additional parts and you can add more notebook, 
even put 3 or 4 or even more notebooks together. I also want to convert it into a wallet.
Erasable ballpoint pen from Pilot is still good for me but its colour is not bold enough in Midori&amp;#39;s paper.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2015 02:41:19 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.dangnamkhanh.com/blog/bullet-journal/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.dangnamkhanh.com/blog/bullet-journal/</guid>
        
        <category>calendar</category>
        
        <category>todo</category>
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>note</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Getting thank letter from Kawahigashi Junior High School</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;　こんにちわ！&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up late yesterday then checked my email. Surprisingly, I got an email about thank letter that sent to me via CSIP office. I joined a talk event at Kawahigashi Junior High School last month about my country and felt incrediblely about Japanese young students and teachers. They event give me a flower and small money as present (It is not voluteering, please do not confuse). Here is me while talking about World Heritages of Vietnam (which were recognized by UNESCO):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015-02-01_Kawahigashi/me_in_Kawahigashi.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;me&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately, they sent me a thankful letter (I guess they have small vacation on New Year Holiday so it is a little bit late). They also give me a CD-R which include all photos of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015-02-01_Kawahigashi/thank-letter-Kawahigashi.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thank letter&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I have to say that it is so amazing about Japanese. They are so cute and thoughtful to me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P/S: you can find some images about this event here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/s/aHsk6DuhxY&quot;&gt;flickr&lt;/a&gt; and another events here: &lt;a href=&quot;/speaking&quot;&gt;speaking-article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;　こんにちわ！&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 02:41:19 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.dangnamkhanh.com/blog/thank-letter-from-kawahigashi-school/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.dangnamkhanh.com/blog/thank-letter-from-kawahigashi-school/</guid>
        
        <category>voluteer</category>
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>japan</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>voluteer</category>
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Customizing tcl Altera Modelsim</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After very long time, I came back to do some HDL coding and simulating. I tried to simulating our lab source code. Since I changed laboratory last year, I cannot use older tools like Xilinx or Modelsim anymore. Due to current lab license, I have to use Altera and its modelsim version for simulating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As my best knowledge, Modelsim Altera version doesn&amp;#39;t allow mix HDL simulation (both VHDL and verilog) and no more than 10,000 lines of code (luckily, verilog is sorter than VHDL). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my new problem that Quartus GUI is so strange to me (I used to do VHDL on Xilinx ISE) and I need to investigate into sub-module. However, everytime I call modelsim it auto runs itself tcl script but I need to use customized script file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you running with modelsim, Altera will automatically generate a tcl file name as: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-&quot; data-lang=&quot;&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;design_name&amp;gt;_run_msim_&amp;lt;level&amp;gt;_&amp;lt;language&amp;gt;.do
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because this file is generated by Altera, therefore you cannot modify it for running (it is overwritten each time you call modelsim).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solution for this problem is one option in Quartus. Click top design, choose setting, go to section EDA Tool, then simulation. In list of options, we have native link settings. So, there are three options: do nothing, compile one module with addtional tcl file and run customized tcl file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015-01-31_custon_Quartus/quartus-option-tcl.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Your options&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best option is just doing nothing then you can run whatever tcl script in modelsim. Moreover, you can find somes another option about linking between Quartus and Modelsim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you very much for reading this article and see you later.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 02:45:19 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.dangnamkhanh.com/blog/customize__Altera-ModelSim/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.dangnamkhanh.com/blog/customize__Altera-ModelSim/</guid>
        
        <category>waveform</category>
        
        <category>altera</category>
        
        <category>hdl</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>modelsim</category>
        
        <category>altera</category>
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Hello!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first post on my own website. I just bought a domain yesterday then tried to figure out how to set up my website.
Firstly, I think I can setup with wordpress for fee but they required me to pay about 10$ per year for this service. So this is just too much because I already paid for my domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Formerly I maintained my personal website in github since last year. Therefore I think that I can use CNAME to point to this for free (it is amazing). I googled it and it is worked. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I put my old website which is actually a one-page html on my new domain but I think it&amp;#39;s just &amp;quot;unprofessionally&amp;quot;. Especially, I need to post some articles but using html and handle link is inconvenient. I tried to google again then find out that I can setup &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;jekyll&lt;/a&gt; to generate my website base on Markdown. I have a lot chances to do with Markdown in the past so it is just easy for me and closes to HTML. After wasting a morning, I finally finished it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I have new host for free with basical function (I think PHP doesn&amp;#39;t work here!). Since I am not professional blogger so I satisfy with this. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you very much for reading this article and see you later.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 02:41:19 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.dangnamkhanh.com/blog/hello/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.dangnamkhanh.com/blog/hello/</guid>
        
        <category>github</category>
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>github-pages</category>
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
