<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Khanh&#39;s Site</title>
    <description>Personal website of Dang Nam Khanh.</description>
    <link>http://www.dangnamkhanh.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.dangnamkhanh.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Customizing tcl Altera Modelsim</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After very long time, I came back to do some HDL coding and simulating. I tried to simulating our lab source code. Since I changed laboratory last year, I cannot use older tools like Xilinx or Modelsim anymore. Due to current lab license, I have to use Altera and its modelsim version for simulating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As my best knowledge, Modelsim Altera version doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow mix HDL simulation (both VHDL and verilog) and no more than 10,000 lines of code (luckily, verilog is sorter than VHDL). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my new problem that Quartus GUI is so strange to me (I used to do VHDL on Xilinx ISE) and I need to investigate into sub-module. However, everytime I call modelsim it auto runs itself tcl script but I need to use customized script file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you running with modelsim, Altera will automatically generate a tcl file name as: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-&quot; data-lang=&quot;&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;design_name&amp;gt;_run_msim_&amp;lt;level&amp;gt;_&amp;lt;language&amp;gt;.do
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because this file is generated by Altera, therefore you cannot modify it for running (it is overwritten each time you call modelsim).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solution for this problem is one option in Quartus. Click top design, choose setting, go to section EDA Tool, then simulation. In list of options, we have native link settings. So, there are three options: do nothing, compile one module with addtional tcl file and run customized tcl file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/quartus-option-tcl.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Your options&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best option is just doing nothing then you can run whatever tcl script in modelsim. Moreover, you can find somes another option about linking between Quartus and Modelsim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you very much for reading this article and see you later.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2015 02:45:19 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.dangnamkhanh.com/blog/modelsim/altera/2015/01/31/customize__Altera-ModelSim/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.dangnamkhanh.com/blog/modelsim/altera/2015/01/31/customize__Altera-ModelSim/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first post on my own website. I just bought a domain yesterday then tried to figure out how to set up my website.
Firstly, I think I can setup with wordpress for fee but they required me to pay about 10$ per year for this service. So this is just too much because I already paid for my domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Formerly I maintained my personal website in github since last year. Therefore I think that I can use CNAME to point to this for free (it is amazing). I googled it and it is worked. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I put my old website which is actually a one-page html on my new domain but I think it&amp;rsquo;s just &amp;ldquo;unprofessionally&amp;rdquo;. Especially, I need to post some articles but using html and handle link is inconvenient. I tried to google again then find out that I can setup &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;jekyll&lt;/a&gt; to generate my website base on Markdown. I have a lot chances to do with Markdown in the past so it is just easy for me and closes to HTML. After wasting a morning, I finally finished it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I have new host for free with basical function (I think PHP doesn&amp;rsquo;t work here!). Since I am not professional blogger so I satisfy with this. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you very much for reading this article and see you later.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 02:41:19 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.dangnamkhanh.com/blog/2015/01/23/hello/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.dangnamkhanh.com/blog/2015/01/23/hello/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
